Preliminary Guide to the Charles Argersinger Papers circa 1970s-circa 2000s
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
Preliminary Guide to the Charles Argersinger Papers
circa 1970s-circa 2000s
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives and Special Collections
MS 2021.06
Argersinger, Charles
11.64 Linear feet of shelf space 10 Boxes
Media, musical scores, compositions, and programs, correspondence, publicity and publication materials, teaching materials, exhibit materials, photographs, music festival materials and other professional papers of Washington State University music professor Charles Argersinger.
Charles Edward Argersinger (1951-2013) was born in Schenectady, NY, and grew up in Arizona. He earned his bachelor's and master's degrees in music from Arizona State University, and his Ph.D. from the University of Minnesota. He taught at California State University, Bakersfield and DePaul University before joining the faculty at Washington State University (WSU). While at WSU, he founded the WSU Festival of Contemporary Art Music in 1989. He retired from WSU in 2009.
This collection consists of media, musical scores, compositions, and programs, correspondence, publicity and publication materials, teaching materials, exhibit materials, photographs, music festival materials and other professional papers of Washington State University music professor Charles Argersinger. Professor Argersinger composed in two main genres: jazz and contemporary art music.
This is an unprocessed collection. Any arrangement reflects either a pre-existing order from the records' creators or previous custodians, or preliminary sorting performed by staff.
This collection is predominantly open and available for research use. However, certain materials in boxes 3, 7 and 9 are restricted until further review by MASC staff due to privacy concerns.
Jana Argersinger donated this collection to the Washington State University Libraries in 2021 (MS.2021.06).
The repository expects to receive additions to this collection.
Charles Argersinger Papers, 1968-2017 (Cage 952)
Washington State University School of Music Records and Photographs, 1922-1977 (Archives 298)
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Argersinger, Charles -- Archives
Washington State University -- Faculty -- Archives
Composers -- Washington (State) -- 20th Century -- Archives; Music -- 20th Century; Music -- 21st Century; Jazz -- 20th Century; Jazz -- 21st Century; Composers -- Washington (State) -- 21st Century -- Archives
Music; Colleges and Universities; Washington (State)
- Musical scores and compositions, 1980-2006 (Box 1)
- Musical scores and compositions, media, 1975-2006 (Box 2)
- Michael Jackson copyright infringement trial, 1993-1995 (Box 3)
  RESTRICTED until further review by MASC staff.
- Musical scores and compositions, 1985-2002 (Box 4)
- Programs and performances, 1974-2007 (Box 5)
- New Music Festival/Festival of Contemporary Art Music materials, including cassettes, CDs, reel to reels, VHS circa 1980s-2000s; floppy discs of Argersinger’s digital records scores circa 1990s, circa 1980s-circa 2000s (Box 6)
- New Music Festival/Festival of Contemporary Art Music materials circa 1980s-2000s; undated photographs; unidentified musical sketches, ideas, and program notes; tenure and promotion review materials circa 1990s; work for Cliff Colnot, Chicago composer, circa 2000s – tenure and promotion review materials, circa 1980s-circa 2000s (Box 7)
- Various scores, circa 1990s-circa 2000s (Box 8)
- MASC exhibit of illustrated manuscripts circa 2000s; musical performances and programs circa 1970s-2000s; publicity and publications circa 1980s-1990s; correspondence circa 1980s-2000s; key pedagogy and student work circa 1970s – correspondence and student work, circa 1970s-circa 2000s (Box 9)
- Oversize materials related to the Festival of Contemporary Art Music, work with Cliff Colnot, and the MASC illuminated manuscripts exhibit, circa 1970s-circa 2000s (Box 10)